<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Love Builds Here]]></title><description><![CDATA[Helpful parenting tips, house projects, and anything else along the way that helps us grow to love more.]]></description><link>https://www.lovebuildshere.com/</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 22:34:10 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[People of the New Day]]></title><description><![CDATA[But on the first day of the week, at early dawn, they went to the tomb, itaking the spices they had prepared. - Luke 24:1 One morning last…]]></description><link>https://www.lovebuildshere.com//people-of-the-new-day/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.lovebuildshere.com//people-of-the-new-day/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But on the first day of the week, at early dawn, they went to the tomb, itaking the spices they had prepared. - Luke 24:1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One morning last week, I woke up around 5:45am. The sky was just starting to change from dark to light, and my mind immediately went to the story of the Resurrection, and the symbolism of the Gospel passages. Matthew says it was “toward the dawn”, Mark says it was “very early”, Luke says it was “early dawn”, and John says “while it was still dark”. In Revelation 22:16, we hear Jesus say, “‘I, Jesus, have sent my angel to testify to you about these things for the churches. I am the root and the descendant of David, the bright morning star.‘” (italics mine).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s impossible to miss. His resurrection points to daybreak. The night is over. Paul says in Romans 13:12,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The night is far gone; the day is at hand. So then let us cast off the works of darkness and put on the armor of light.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are people of the new day. In Romans, we see that in light of the new day, we are also called to “cast off the works of darkness and put on the armor of light”. We do that through understanding the time we now live in, walking like we should as new people (v.13), and constantly putting on Jesus (v.14), or abiding in Him (remember John 15?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each day is not just another day. It is the passing of time that sees the sun break a little more over the horizon. Let us live like people of the new day.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dark Horses]]></title><description><![CDATA[It’s one of my favorite Switchfoot songs. A solid rock anthem, started with the lines: I MADE MY MISTAKES, I SEEN MY HEART CAVE IN, I GOT MY…]]></description><link>https://www.lovebuildshere.com//dark-horses/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.lovebuildshere.com//dark-horses/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;It’s one of my favorite Switchfoot songs. A solid rock anthem, started with the lines:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I MADE MY MISTAKES, I SEEN MY HEART CAVE IN, I GOT MY SCARS, I BEEN TO HELL AND BACK AGAIN&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I think it’s the story of most strong-willed men like myself. I didn’t fit. And sometimes, frankly, I still don’t. I was born to the beat of my own drum. But, I was made who I am by a God that knows what to do with someone like me, and that, my friends, gives me hope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m drawn to Psalm 32, one of the key passages for our church. In verse 9, David instructs the hearer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BE NOT LIKE A HORSE OR A MULE, WITHOUT UNDERSTANDING, WHICH MUST BE CURBED WITH BIT AND BRIDLE, OR
IT WILL NOT STAY NEAR YOU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, God gave me a picture. And the picture was of myself as a wild stallion (no, not the weird, romance novel type). The stallion is good and strong, but without training and guidance, he is limited in his usefulness. What the stallion needed was someone &lt;strong&gt;trusted&lt;/strong&gt; to come alongside, and, together, what a force.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, there are some interesting things in that picture. First, that word &lt;strong&gt;trust&lt;/strong&gt; is key. The relationship between horse and rider is a deep one, and one that we see throughout history usually lasting throughout the life of one or the other. Think of great ancient generals, and chances are that you’ll see a specific horse in there somewhere. Second, both the rider and the horse are necessary. One without the other doesn’t make much sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That draws us back to Psalm 32:7, where the writer indicates that rich, trusting relationship he has with the LORD:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YOU ARE A HIDING PLACE FOR ME; YOU PRESERVE ME FROM TROUBLE; YOU SURROUND ME WITH SHOUTS OF
DELIVERANCE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine that. &lt;strong&gt;The LORD, the God of promise and covenant, surrounds him with shouts of deliverance.&lt;/strong&gt; That verse shouts trust and faith. How did he get there though? Does it just happen? Look back even further at verses 3-6:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FOR WHEN I KEPT SILENT, MY BONES WASTED AWAY THROUGH MY GROANING ALL DAY LONG. FOR DAY AND NIGHT
YOUR HAND WAS HEAVY UPON ME; MY STRENGTH WAS DRIED UP AS BY THE HEAT OF SUMMER.
I ACKNOWLEDGED MY SIN TO YOU, AND I DID NOT COVER MY INIQUITY; I SAID, “I WILL CONFESS MY
TRANSGRESSIONS TO THE LORD,” AND YOU FORGAVE THE INIQUITY OF MY SIN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The writer had come to know God &lt;strong&gt;through a relationship over time&lt;/strong&gt;, that involved a deep realization of who he was and who God was. An understanding of his sin and the effects of it, and an understanding of a God that is there even when we are silent, but who is willing to forgive all of the shame, guilt and evil of our sin the moment that we confess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is that relationship and understanding that draws the writer to trust and enjoy the steadfast love of the Lord, and to instruct others to do the same (verses 6,8,9). These are the people that are truly blessed (verses 1-2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no other way. Trust. Live a life of confession and openness before Him. If you trust Him, his steadfast love will surround you, and you will be blessed. 1 John 1:9 would echo this: &lt;strong&gt;“If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just to forgive us our sins and to cleanse us from all unrighteousness.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May we that are strong men embrace who we are, but not be like stubborn horses or mules. May we instead draw near to the Master, and trust Him by being quick to confess, and quick to open ourselves before Him who sees us exactly as we are anyways. And, as we do that, may we hear His shouts of deliverance over us, feel the warmth of His steadfast love, and know His protection that keeps us from trouble.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>